<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://zeyuzhang1901.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://zeyuzhang1901.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-24T20:35:06+00:00</updated><id>https://zeyuzhang1901.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>I am a third-year Ph.D. student in the Department of Statistics and Data Science at Northwestern University. My research focuses on knowledge leakage in large language models, with particular emphasis on settings that involve complex reasoning and chain-of-thought processes. I study how and when sensitive or unintended information may be exposed during multi-step inference, and I am interested in principled methods for detecting, characterizing, and mitigating such leakage. In parallel, I work on fine-tuning language models using reinforcement learning–based approaches, including RLHF, Direct Preference Optimization (DPO), and related algorithms, with the goal of improving alignment, robustness, and controllability. Outside of research, I am deeply committed to an active lifestyle. I follow a structured workout program and train almost every day, viewing physical discipline as a natural complement to intellectual rigor. I enjoy a wide range of sports, with basketball being my favorite, and I am particularly drawn to long-distance running for both its physical demands and its meditative rhythm. These activities keep me grounded, energized, and continuously motivated—both on and off the track. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">How I Generate Paper Figures with Claude and Gemini</title><link href="https://zeyuzhang1901.github.io/blog/2026/generating-paper-figures-with-gemini/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I Generate Paper Figures with Claude and Gemini"/><published>2026-01-22T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-22T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://zeyuzhang1901.github.io/blog/2026/generating-paper-figures-with-gemini</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zeyuzhang1901.github.io/blog/2026/generating-paper-figures-with-gemini/"><![CDATA[<p>I was working on my paper and needed to create an illustration for the evaluation pipeline. You know, one of those architecture diagrams with boxes and arrows that show how everything flows together. The kind of figure that takes hours to draw in PowerPoint or Figma, where you spend more time aligning boxes than actually thinking about your research.</p> <p>I really didn’t want to draw it myself.</p> <p>So I thought — why not try AI image generation? I’d heard Gemini’s image generation (specifically the model I call “Gemini Banana Pro”) was getting pretty good. Maybe it could save me some time.</p> <p>Spoiler: it did. But not in the way I initially expected.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="the-failed-first-attempt">The Failed First Attempt</h2> <p>My first instinct was simple: just describe what I want and let Gemini do its thing. I wrote something like “generate an evaluation pipeline with 4 phases, use boxes and arrows, make it look professional.”</p> <p>The result was… let’s just say creative. The flowchart looked more like abstract art than a technical diagram. Text was garbled, arrows pointed randomly, and it clearly had no idea what an “evaluation pipeline” actually meant in the context of my work.</p> <p>But here’s the thing — I still didn’t want to draw it myself. This failure actually motivated me to think deeper: <em>why</em> was Gemini failing?</p> <hr/> <h2 id="the-insight">The Insight</h2> <p>After staring at those failed attempts, I realized the problem:</p> <p><strong>Gemini doesn’t understand my pipeline from a vague description.</strong> It doesn’t have access to my code, doesn’t know the specific components, and can’t infer the relationships between different parts. It’s like asking someone to draw your house when they’ve never seen it — they’ll draw <em>a</em> house, but not <em>your</em> house.</p> <p>But then I thought about it more:</p> <ul> <li><strong>I’m good at high-level understanding</strong> — I know there are 4 phases, I know the overall flow, I know what’s important</li> <li><strong>I’m terrible at writing exhaustive prompts</strong> — listing every single component, every arrow, every label is tedious and I’ll miss things</li> <li><strong>Claude Opus 4.5 can read my code</strong> — it can understand every function, every data flow, every detail</li> <li><strong>Gemini is good at generating images</strong> — but only when given precise instructions</li> </ul> <p>The solution became obvious: <strong>use Claude to bridge the gap</strong>. I provide the high-level structure, Claude reads my code and generates a detailed prompt, then Gemini creates the image.</p> <p>Let me show you exactly how this worked.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="step-1-asking-claude-for-a-detailed-prompt">Step 1: Asking Claude for a Detailed Prompt</h2> <p>I started by giving Claude the context about my pipeline. Claude had already seen my code in our conversation, so it understood the implementation details. Here’s what I asked:</p> <details><summary>Click to see my prompt to Claude</summary> <p>I think now you are pretty clear about the evaluation process (detection pipeline) and the temporal llm agent architecture. Now I want to create two illustrative images to show in the paper. It should show the readers the architecture of these two pipelines, and each of them should let the reader quickly know how the pipeline work, and the image should highlight the contribution and special parts of the pipeline (to point out our innovation).</p> <p>Now let’s first start with the evaluation pipeline (detection). You should call it evaluation pipeline (not detection pipeline). Now please give me a professional, informative, rigorous and high-quality prompt for the image generation model nano banana pro from google to create a good illustrative image. This image will be shown on the top of the corresponding page of the evaluation pipeline section (section “Leakage Detection Pipeline”). It will take two columns on the top of that page, and then also give a detailed, rigorous and professional caption for the image. It should concisely describe the whole pipeline and highlight the important parts for the reader to quickly understand the pipeline. I will copy your prompt to that model directly and then see what image it generate.</p> </details> <p>Notice how my prompt is high-level — I’m describing <em>what</em> I want, not <em>how</em> to draw it. I mentioned there are phases, I mentioned highlighting contributions, but I didn’t list every single component. That’s Claude’s job.</p> <p>Claude came back with this detailed prompt for Gemini:</p> <details><summary>Click to see Claude’s generated prompt for Gemini</summary> <p>Create a professional academic figure showing a 4-phase evaluation pipeline for temporal knowledge leakage detection in LLM predictions. The figure should be horizontal, suitable for a two-column academic paper layout.</p> <p>Layout (left to right flow):</p> <ul> <li>Start with INPUT box on the left containing: “Rationale R”, “Reference time t_ref”, “Task context”</li> </ul> <p>PHASE 1 (Claim Extraction):</p> <ul> <li>Box labeled “Phase 1: Claim Extraction”</li> <li>Show rationale being decomposed into multiple small boxes representing claims</li> <li>Each claim box has a category label tag (A1, A2, A3, A4, A5, B1, B2)</li> <li>Output arrow splits into TWO parallel paths</li> </ul> <p>PARALLEL PROCESSING (Phase 2 and Phase 3 run simultaneously):</p> <ul> <li>Use dashed vertical line or visual indicator showing these run in parallel</li> </ul> <p>PHASE 2 (upper parallel branch):</p> <ul> <li>Box labeled “Phase 2: Shapley Computation”</li> <li>Show mathematical symbol φ₁, φ₂, … φₙ</li> <li>Small icon suggesting Monte Carlo sampling</li> <li>Output: “Shapley values {φᵢ}”</li> </ul> <p>PHASE 3 (lower parallel branch):</p> <ul> <li>Box labeled “Phase 3: Leakage Detection”</li> <li>IMPORTANT: Show a decision tree or branching logic: <ul> <li>A4/A5 → “Always Leaked” (marked with red/warning color, NO search icon)</li> <li>B1/B2 → “Never Leaked” (marked with green/safe color, NO search icon)</li> <li>A1/A2/A3 → “Search Required” (with search/magnifying glass icon)</li> </ul> </li> <li>Highlight “40-80% claims skip search” as efficiency callout</li> <li>Output: “Leakage indicators {ℓᵢ}”</li> </ul> <p>PHASE 4 (Metrics):</p> <ul> <li>Box labeled “Phase 4: Metrics Aggregation”</li> <li>Two arrows from Phase 2 and Phase 3 converge here</li> <li>Show formulas or text: “OLR”, “Shapley-DCLR”</li> <li>Output box on right: “Leakage Report” with metrics</li> </ul> <p>Visual style:</p> <ul> <li>Clean, minimalist academic style with light colors</li> <li>Use arrows to show data flow</li> <li>Highlight the parallel execution and category-based optimization as key innovations</li> <li>Use consistent color coding: blue for processing phases, green for valid/safe, red/orange for leaked/warning</li> <li>Professional typography suitable for academic publication</li> <li>White or light gray background</li> </ul> </details> <p>See how detailed this is? Claude specified exact component names from my code, the mathematical notation, the color coding, even details like “40-80% claims skip search” which is a key contribution of my work. This is exactly the kind of exhaustive prompt I would never write myself.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="the-first-generated-image">The First Generated Image</h2> <p>I copied Claude’s prompt directly to Gemini Banana Pro and got this:</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Version 1: The first attempt. Overall structure is there, but there are several issues... </div> <p>Not bad for a first attempt! The overall flow is there, the parallel processing is shown, and the color coding looks reasonable. But when I looked closely, there were problems.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="step-2-claude-analyzes-the-problems">Step 2: Claude Analyzes the Problems</h2> <p>I showed this image to Claude and asked it to analyze with a critical eye:</p> <details><summary>Click to see my prompt asking Claude to analyze</summary> <p>Do you think it’s a proper image for our paper. Please carefully read it in a professional and rigorous view, think deeply about our pipeline, and then give out some advice to improve this pipeline image. You should form all the advice and modification into a prompt and then I will copy it to the image generation model to generate a refined image.</p> </details> <p>Claude came back with a detailed analysis. Here’s what it found:</p> <p><strong>What works well:</strong></p> <ul> <li>Overall left-to-right flow is clear</li> <li>Parallel processing indicator between Phase 2 and 3</li> <li>Category-based branching in Phase 3 with color coding</li> <li>The efficiency callout for skipping search</li> </ul> <p><strong>Issues that need fixing:</strong></p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Issue</th> <th>Problem</th> <th>Fix</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td>Phase 4 naming</td> <td>“Shapley-based Dynamic Claims Leakage Rate” is WRONG</td> <td>Should be “Decision-Critical Leakage Rate”</td> </tr> <tr> <td>DCLR formula</td> <td>Shows Σ(φᵢ · ℓᵢ) which is incomplete</td> <td>Should show full formula with denominator and absolute value</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Callout style</td> <td>“highly efficient!” is too informal/promotional</td> <td>Use academic tone: “40-80% of claims require no search”</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Phase 1 claims</td> <td>Claim numbering is confusing (shows Claim 6, 7, 8 with wrong categories)</td> <td>Use cleaner representation: c₁, c₂, …, cₙ</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Missing detail</td> <td>Phase 3 doesn’t show comparison with t_ref</td> <td>Add “τ(c) &gt; t_ref ?” for A1-A3 branch</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>This is exactly why I use Claude for this — I might have noticed one or two issues, but Claude caught things like the incorrect metric naming and the incomplete formula that I could have easily missed.</p> <p>Claude then generated a refinement prompt:</p> <details><summary>Click to see Claude’s refinement prompt</summary> <p>Refine this academic figure for a temporal leakage evaluation pipeline. Make the following specific corrections and improvements:</p> <p>CORRECTIONS (CRITICAL):</p> <ol> <li>In Phase 4, change “Shapley-based Dynamic Claims Leakage Rate” to “Shapley-weighted Decision-Critical Leakage Rate (Shapley-DCLR)”</li> <li> <table> <tbody> <tr> <td>Fix the Shapley-DCLR formula to show the COMPLETE formula: (Σ</td> <td>φᵢ</td> <td>·ℓᵢ) / (Σ</td> <td>φᵢ</td> <td>) - it MUST include the denominator and absolute values</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> </li> <li>Change the informal callout “40-80% claims skip search, highly efficient!” to a more academic tone: “40-80% of claims determined without search”</li> </ol> <p>IMPROVEMENTS:</p> <ol> <li>In Phase 1, simplify the claim representation: show rationale R being decomposed into claims c₁, c₂, …, cₙ, each with a single category tag (use colors: orange for A1-A3, red for A4-A5, green for B1-B2)</li> <li>In Phase 3, for the “SEARCH REQUIRED” branch (A1, A2, A3), add a small label showing the comparison: “τ(c) &gt; t_ref ?” to indicate we’re comparing determination date against reference time</li> <li>In the OUTPUT box, remove “other relevant aggregated metrics” - just show “OLR: X%” and “Shapley-DCLR: Y%”</li> <li>Make the parallel processing text more readable - either horizontal or use a cleaner vertical label</li> <li>Use consistent academic styling throughout - no exclamation marks, promotional language, or informal callouts</li> </ol> <p>KEEP:</p> <ul> <li>The overall left-to-right flow structure</li> <li>The phase box styling and colors</li> <li>The three-way branching in Phase 3 (A4/A5 → Always Leaked, A1-A3 → Search, B1/B2 → Never Leaked)</li> <li>The Monte Carlo sampling indicator in Phase 2</li> <li>The color scheme (red for leaked, green for safe, blue for processing)</li> </ul> <p>Style: Clean, minimalist, professional academic figure suitable for a top-tier venue like KDD/NeurIPS. White background, clear typography.</p> </details> <hr/> <h2 id="the-second-generated-image">The Second Generated Image</h2> <p>I fed this refinement prompt to Gemini and got:</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Version 2: Better! The naming is fixed, the callout is more academic, but there are still issues with the formula... </div> <p>Better! But still not perfect.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="step-3-one-more-round">Step 3: One More Round</h2> <p>I showed this to Claude again and asked for another analysis:</p> <details><summary>Click to see my second analysis request</summary> <p>This is it’s modified version, let’s do what we just did one more time, check every details in the image with your understanding of the pipeline, and then check if the image fit your rigorous, professional high-standard requirements. Then give me a refine prompt for the model to modify the image it just generated.</p> <p>Also I noticed that in phase 4, the equation is not complete. It use the words as the left hand side of the equation, which is not good looking. Please ask the model to write the complete equation.</p> </details> <p>Claude found more issues:</p> <p><strong>Phase 1 - Claim Extraction:</strong></p> <ul> <li>❌ Claim numbering is still problematic: c₃ appears twice, c₆ appears twice, c₇ appears twice</li> <li>Should be c₁, c₂, c₃, c₄, c₅, c₆, c₇ each appearing exactly ONCE</li> </ul> <p><strong>Phase 2 - Shapley Computation:</strong></p> <ul> <li>✓ φ₁, φ₂, …, φₙ shown correctly</li> <li>✓ Monte Carlo Sampling indicated</li> <li>✓ Clean and correct</li> </ul> <p><strong>Phase 3 - Leakage Detection:</strong></p> <ul> <li>✓ τ(c) &gt; t_ref? added for A1-A3 branch (good!)</li> <li>✓ Callout is now academic tone</li> <li>❌ “NO search icon” text is redundant</li> </ul> <p><strong>Phase 4 - Metrics Aggregation:</strong></p> <ul> <li>✓ Name corrected to “Decision-Critical Leakage Rate”</li> <li> <table> <tbody> <tr> <td>❌ CRITICAL: Shapley-DCLR formula is STILL INCOMPLETE - shows Σ(φᵢ · ℓᵢ) but missing denominator Σ</td> <td>φᵢ</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> </li> <li>❌ Using words as left-hand side of equation looks unprofessional</li> </ul> <p>Claude generated another refinement prompt:</p> <details><summary>Click to see Claude’s second refinement prompt</summary> <p>Further refine this academic figure with the following specific corrections:</p> <p>CRITICAL FORMULA CORRECTIONS IN PHASE 4:</p> <ol> <li> <p>The Shapley-DCLR formula is INCOMPLETE. Replace the current formula with the COMPLETE equation:</p> <table> <tbody> <tr> <td>Shapley-DCLR = (Σᵢ</td> <td>φᵢ</td> <td>· ℓᵢ) / (Σᵢ</td> <td>φᵢ</td> <td>)</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <table> <tbody> <tr> <td>Show this as a proper fraction with numerator on top and denominator on bottom. The absolute value bars</td> <td>φᵢ</td> <td>are essential.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> </li> <li> <p>For OLR, show the complete equation:</p> <p>OLR = (1/n) Σᵢ ℓᵢ</p> </li> <li> <p>Do NOT use words like “OLR (Overall Leakage Rate) =” as the left-hand side. Use proper mathematical notation:</p> <ul> <li>First line: “OLR = (1/n) Σᵢ ℓᵢ”</li> <li> <table> <tbody> <tr> <td>Second line: “Shapley-DCLR = (Σᵢ</td> <td>φᵢ</td> <td>· ℓᵢ) / (Σᵢ</td> <td>φᵢ</td> <td>)”</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> </li> </ul> <p>The metric names can be shown as labels above or beside the equations, but the equations themselves should be complete mathematical expressions.</p> </li> </ol> <p>PHASE 1 CORRECTIONS:</p> <ol> <li>Fix the claim numbering - each claim should appear exactly ONCE: Show: c₁(A1), c₂(A2), c₃(A3), c₄(A4), c₅(A5), c₆(B1), c₇(B2) Arrange them in a cleaner grid or flow from R, with no duplicate claim numbers.</li> </ol> <p>PHASE 3 CORRECTIONS:</p> <ol> <li>Remove the redundant “NO search icon” text under “ALWAYS LEAKED” and “NEVER LEAKED” boxes. The visual already clearly shows no magnifying glass - the text is unnecessary.</li> </ol> <p>KEEP EVERYTHING ELSE:</p> <ul> <li>The overall layout and flow</li> <li>The parallel processing indicator</li> <li>The color scheme (blue phases, red for leaked, green for safe)</li> <li>The τ(c) &gt; t_ref? label on the A1-A3 branch</li> <li>The “40-80% of claims determined without search” callout</li> <li>The clean OUTPUT box</li> </ul> <p>Style: Ensure all mathematical notation is crisp, properly formatted, and publication-ready for a top-tier venue.</p> </details> <hr/> <h2 id="the-final-image">The Final Image</h2> <p>Third time’s the charm:</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v3-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/gemini-figures/pipeline_v3.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Version 3: The final result. Clean, accurate, publication-ready. </div> <p>I showed this to Claude and asked if it was ready:</p> <details><summary>Click to see my final check</summary> <p>What about this version, do you think we need further improvement? Or this one already meets your standard for our KDD paper (professional, rigorous, and high-quality). Give me your reason.</p> </details> <p>Claude’s response: <strong>“This version meets my standards for a KDD paper.”</strong></p> <p>Here’s Claude’s final assessment:</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Element</th> <th>Status</th> <th>Details</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td>Phase 1</td> <td>✓</td> <td>c₁ through c₇ each appears exactly once with correct category tags</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Phase 2</td> <td>✓</td> <td>φ₁, φ₂, …, φₙ with Monte Carlo Sampling indicator</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Phase 3</td> <td>✓</td> <td>Clean three-way branching, τ(c) &gt; t_ref? shown, no redundant text</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Phase 4 - OLR</td> <td>✓</td> <td>Complete formula: OLR = (1/n) Σᵢ ℓᵢ</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Phase 4 - DCLR</td> <td>✓</td> <td>Complete formula with denominator and absolute values</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Layout</td> <td>✓</td> <td>Clear left-to-right flow, parallel processing indicated</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Style</td> <td>✓</td> <td>Clean, professional, no informal callouts</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p><strong>Why it meets publication standards:</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Mathematical Rigor</strong>: Both formulas are now complete and correctly formatted with proper fraction notation</li> <li><strong>Visual Clarity</strong>: The pipeline flow is immediately understandable — a reader can grasp the four phases and their relationships at a glance</li> <li><strong>Technical Accuracy</strong>: The category-based branching in Phase 3 correctly shows the key contribution</li> <li><strong>Professional Appearance</strong>: Clean color scheme, consistent typography, no promotional language</li> <li><strong>Self-Contained</strong>: The figure tells the complete story without requiring the reader to reference the text</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="what-i-learned">What I Learned</h2> <p>This whole process took about 20-30 minutes and 3 iterations. Compare that to the hours I would have spent manually drawing it in PowerPoint or Figma.</p> <p>But more importantly, here’s why this workflow actually works:</p> <blockquote class="block-tip"> <h5 id="tip">TIP</h5> <p><strong>The key insight</strong>: Humans are good at high-level thinking — understanding the overall structure, knowing what’s important, deciding what looks “right.” AI models are good at details — reading code, extracting every component, writing exhaustive prompts.</p> </blockquote> <p>The workflow leverages each participant’s strengths:</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Task</th> <th>Best Done By</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td>Understanding overall structure</td> <td>Me</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Extracting implementation details from code</td> <td>Claude</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Synthesizing into comprehensive prompt</td> <td>Claude</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Generating visual output</td> <td>Gemini</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Identifying visual errors</td> <td>Me + Claude</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Making final quality decisions</td> <td>Me</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>You’re not asking any single agent to do everything. You’re orchestrating a collaboration where each participant does what they’re best at.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="try-it-yourself">Try It Yourself</h2> <p>If you want to try this for your own paper figures:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Give Claude your code and high-level structure</strong> — You don’t need to write a detailed prompt. Just say “there are 4 phases” or “the agent has these components.” Claude will read your code and fill in the details.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Feed Claude’s prompt to Gemini</strong> — Copy it directly. Don’t edit it (unless you spot something obviously wrong).</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Show the result back to Claude</strong> — Ask it to analyze critically. Tell it to find ALL errors, not just the obvious ones.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Iterate 2-3 times</strong> — In my experience, it usually converges within 3 iterations.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Do a final quality check</strong> — Ask Claude to compare against high-quality figures from top venues.</p> </li> </ol> <p>The first time might feel slow as you figure out the workflow. But once you have it down, you can generate publication-quality figures much faster than drawing them yourself.</p> <p>And honestly? The figures often end up better than what I would have drawn manually, because Claude catches details and inconsistencies that I would have missed.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="resources">Resources</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://ai.google.dev/">Gemini Image Generation</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.anthropic.com/claude">Claude</a></li> <li>For examples of high-quality architecture diagrams, check out spotlight papers from NeurIPS, ICML, and ICLR</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="tutorials"/><category term="AI"/><category term="tools"/><category term="workflow"/><category term="code"/><category term="image"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A real story of creating publication-quality architecture diagrams using AI — showing every prompt, every iteration, and every mistake along the way]]></summary></entry></feed>